Indira Murugan

(636)-346-5829)

indiramurugan8@gmail.com https://github.com/IndiraMur https://www.linkedin.com/in/indira-murugan-74349b152

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATION

Versatile, motivated Programmer/Developer with specializing in web and backend development. Proven supportive and enthusiastic team member with the ability to formulate problems, think creatively about solutions, and express a solution clearly and accurately. Experienced in assessing and prioritizing the urgency of requests to maximize efficiency and completion. Excellent at time management skills Including timely submission of required reports and documentation. Demonstrated ability to learn complex skills and concepts quickly and effectively.

Key Skills

- Python and C#
- Flask and ASP.Net
- MySQL, SQLAlchemy, Entity
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Visual Studio, MVC, GitHub, Git Bash
- ORACLE PL/SQL
- COBOL
- BASIC, FOX, DBASE
- MS Dos, UNIX

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

LiftOff LaunchCode, STL-2018

• Focusing on completion of project through agile planning and communications practices involving Sprint Planning, Daily Stand-up, Iteration review, Retrospective, organized around 2 week sprints.

PROJECTS:

KashiHomeFood

- Developed project on asp.net MVC framework with core C# on Visual Studio IDE.
- Used CSS, Bootstrap for the front end development.
- Installing and connecting the MS SQL DB with Visual Studio IDE using the SQLDataSourceControl.

Completed LC101 - LaunchCode course July 2017 - Dec 2017

- Gained knowledge in Universal Web concepts: HTML tags and forms, CSS selectors and style rules, Model-View-Controller design for web applications, retrieved and updated data using databases / SQL, Python as back-end language, Version control using Github.
- Proficient in programming: Core C#, C# collections, Data types, Static modifiers, objects and classes, class Inheritance, Polymorphism and Interfaces.
- Adept in creating and configuring controllers, persistent model classes via ADO.NET, created views using Razor templates.
- Acquired Skills in Python programming language: Data types and type casting, Mathematical and comparison operators, Data structures (Lists and Dictionaries), Created Functions, object and classes.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Volunteered at LaunchCode, St. Louis, Missouri July 2018 - August 2018

Helped new LaunchCode students in the class assignments

Target Corporation, Chesterfield, MO OCT 2016 – MAY 2017

• As a Cashier

Lakhotia Computer Centre Coimbatore India JAN 1998 – MAY 1998

As a faculty

Vigyan Bhavan, New Delhi, India MARCH 1997 – AUGUST 1997

 Managed IT projects as "Project Coordinator" and has hands on experience in setting up IT infrastructure.

EDUCATION

•	LC101 LaunchCode, St. Louis, MO	Dec 2017
•	Masters in Computer application, IGNOU, New Delhi, India	Jan 2000
•	Diploma in Computer Application , UPTRON ACL, Faridabad, India	July 1994
•	Bachelors of Commerce, University of Kurushetra, Haryana, India	June 1993